<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>
	Comments on: Stubborn client insists on no Sex	</title>
	<atom:link href="/2009/04/03/174/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/2009/04/03/174/</link>
	<description>Технический перевод и локализация. IT Translation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2009 09:06:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>
		By: Writer Yuri Matthew Ryuntyu		</title>
		<link>/2009/04/03/174/#comment-152</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Writer Yuri Matthew Ryuntyu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2009 09:06:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.slovotolk.com/?p=174#comment-152</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[So do I, but I can see the point of making the distinction now.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So do I, but I can see the point of making the distinction now.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Михаил		</title>
		<link>/2009/04/03/174/#comment-151</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Михаил]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2009 19:40:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.slovotolk.com/?p=174#comment-151</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Меня тоже заинтересовала эта дискуссия, и я все ждал, когда выскажутся носители языка.

&lt;strong&gt;Великобритания:&lt;/strong&gt;
The use of &quot;gender&quot; on forms, etc. instead of &quot;sex&quot;, is regrettably modish and almost universally adopted now in the UK, although it is, of course, grammatically wrong, except in relation to grammar. It is all part of the mealy-mouthed Blairification of our beloved language along with all the &quot;political correctness&quot; now essential if one wishes to advance up that slippery ladder.
I&#039;ve had this argument many times with officialdom, all to no avail. They won&#039;t be budged.
I&#039;d try to stick to &quot;sex&quot;, but if the client insists, then it has to be admitted that &quot;gender&quot; will be found all too frequently in the context concerned and the client will thus be able to justify his preference.

&lt;strong&gt;США:&lt;/strong&gt;
I think that Gender Studies scholars define gender as &quot;performative&quot; and sex as biological/genetic.... or something like that. I find the terminology in this area a little confusing.

The impression I get is that a transgender person born biologically female but living as a man would be considered as belonging to the male &quot;gender&quot; under this definition, but perhaps not the male &quot;sex.&quot;

&lt;strong&gt;А это любопытное продолжение:&lt;/strong&gt;
Absolutely. Gender is how you live. Sex is yer bits and bobs.
So for example, if you had a pre-op transexual with a bank account, he or she (in all senses!) could choose the gender that may sure they got letters addressed to Mr or Ms or whatever as they liked, without having to actually lie about their sex on the form. Something like that, anyway.

And I too used to be a member of the &quot;sex for people (nurse, the screens!) and gender for grammar&quot; club, but I can see the point of making the distinction now. I&#039;m fine with the old fashioned way, and I use it in my translations, but if a client asked, I&#039;d be happy to go with gender.

Куда катится мир :)]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Меня тоже заинтересовала эта дискуссия, и я все ждал, когда выскажутся носители языка.</p>
<p><strong>Великобритания:</strong><br />
The use of &#8220;gender&#8221; on forms, etc. instead of &#8220;sex&#8221;, is regrettably modish and almost universally adopted now in the UK, although it is, of course, grammatically wrong, except in relation to grammar. It is all part of the mealy-mouthed Blairification of our beloved language along with all the &#8220;political correctness&#8221; now essential if one wishes to advance up that slippery ladder.<br />
I&#8217;ve had this argument many times with officialdom, all to no avail. They won&#8217;t be budged.<br />
I&#8217;d try to stick to &#8220;sex&#8221;, but if the client insists, then it has to be admitted that &#8220;gender&#8221; will be found all too frequently in the context concerned and the client will thus be able to justify his preference.</p>
<p><strong>США:</strong><br />
I think that Gender Studies scholars define gender as &#8220;performative&#8221; and sex as biological/genetic&#8230;. or something like that. I find the terminology in this area a little confusing.</p>
<p>The impression I get is that a transgender person born biologically female but living as a man would be considered as belonging to the male &#8220;gender&#8221; under this definition, but perhaps not the male &#8220;sex.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>А это любопытное продолжение:</strong><br />
Absolutely. Gender is how you live. Sex is yer bits and bobs.<br />
So for example, if you had a pre-op transexual with a bank account, he or she (in all senses!) could choose the gender that may sure they got letters addressed to Mr or Ms or whatever as they liked, without having to actually lie about their sex on the form. Something like that, anyway.</p>
<p>And I too used to be a member of the &#8220;sex for people (nurse, the screens!) and gender for grammar&#8221; club, but I can see the point of making the distinction now. I&#8217;m fine with the old fashioned way, and I use it in my translations, but if a client asked, I&#8217;d be happy to go with gender.</p>
<p>Куда катится мир :)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
